Finding Aid for Louis Kuplan sound recordings, 1970-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Louis Kuplan sound recordings 1970-1978
Kuplan, Louis.
142 audiotapes (in 4 boxes) reel-to-reel tapes
95104 Aa 2
Lecturer and consultant on aging, retirement planning, and related topics. Sound recordings of San Francisco television program, "A gift of time," that Kuplan produced and hosted.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The tapes came from the University of Michigan Institute of Gerontology (donor no. 6160 ) in 1984.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Louis Kuplan was an expert in matters relating to aging and the concerns of the elderly. To focus attention on these issues, Kuplan used the media as much as possible. From 1954 to 1960, he was editor of Maturity magazine; and from 1970 to 1978, he was moderator and producer of KRON-TV's program in San Francisco entitled "A Gift of Time."
The Kuplan collection consists of sound recordings of his television program "A Gift of Time." The collection has been arranged chronologically, dating from 1970 to 1978. The tapes are all 7 in. reel-to-reel and play at 7 1/2 ips. The topics of the programs relate to concerns of the elderly. Guests on the program included important experts in the field of gerontology.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Kuplan, Louis, 1906-; Aging.; Gerontology.; Retirement.
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.
- "A gift of time" sound recordings, 7 in.; 7 1/2 ips
  - Initial Program February 1, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Physical Health", with Leon Lewis February 8, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Mental Health in the later Years", with Frances M. Carp February 22, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Federal Programs on Aging", with John B. Martin May 3, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Foot Care for the Elderly", with Drs. P. Gardner and L. Levy May 31, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Hearing Problems in the later Years", with Dr. S. H. Baron June 7, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Nutrition and Money Management for the Elderly", with Nilda Gemple, Home Economist, and Louisa Fletcher, Home Economist June 21, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Dental Care", with Herman Kaplan, and Arthur J. Krul June 28, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Interview with older persons", with Harry Sussman -- Jennie M. Charters June 5, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Housing for the Elderly" March 14, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Legislators on Housing" March 21, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Defensive Driving for Older Persons", with Stanley Kilcoyne March 23, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Employment Opportunities", with Elmer H. Maack April 4, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Arthritis and the Older Person", with William C. Kuzell April 18, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "The Black Elderly", with Hobart C. Jackson April 25, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Replacement of the Arthritic Hip", with Ralph Soto-Hall May 2, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Education for the Elderly", with Jack London May 9, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "San Francisco Senior Hobby Show", with Elean Thomas May 16, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "The Family" May 30, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "California White House Conference on Aging, Sacramento" June 6, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Safety in Streets", with Genevieve Bayreuther July 11, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Homes for the Aging", with Lloyd W. Halverson July 18, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "The Aging Entrepreneur" August 15, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Trade Unions and the Older Member", Part I, with Leo Perliss, AFL-CIO September 5, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Trade Unions and the Older Member", Part II, with Leo Perlis September 12, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Crimes Against the Elderly", with Evelle Younger, California Attorney-General, and Juna Sherwood, his assistant October 3, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "The White House Conference on Aging" 1971 with Arthur S. Flemming, October 24, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Cardiology and the Aging", with Hollister Brewster November 7, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Cardiac Radiology and the Older Patient", with I. Roger Pyle November 14, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Heart Surgery and the Older Person", with Elias S. Hanna November 21, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Emeritus University", with Jeffery Smith December 5, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "The Older Chinese", with Lambert Choy December 19, 1971 (Box 1)
  - "Interviews at 1971 WHCOA, Washington, D.C.", with C. Tibbitts, D. Kent, Huet, Fulgrass, January 1, 1972 (Box 1)
  - "Interviews at 1971 WHCOA, Washington, D.C.", with Ewan Claque, H. Cruikshank, Paillat, Hayden, January 16, 1972 (Box 1)
  - "California Panel on WHCOA", with Van Frank, Schultz, Kilcoyne January 23, 1972 (Box 1)
  - "California Panel Discussion on 1971 WHCOA", with B. Russell, Dr. Beverfeldt, S. Yuen, January 30, 1972 (Box 1)
  - "California Discussion on 1971 WHCOA", with J. Levy and Gertrude Hall, February 6, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Retirement", with Gordon Streib February 20, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "National Council of Senior Citizens", with Nelson Cruikshank February 27, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Hip Replacement", with R. Soto-Hall, Hugo Kemp March 19, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Schools of Nursing and the Older Patient", with University of San Francisco School of Nursing March 26, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "The U.S. Senate and the Older American", with Senator Alan Cranston April 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Panel on Hearing and Speech Problems of Older Persons" April 16, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Panel Discussion Early Retirement" June 4, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Panel Discussion on Jobs for Mature Women" June 11, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Panel Discussion on Early Retirement", Part II June 18, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Strokes and the Elderly", with W. Bradford DeLong June 18, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Discussion on Stroke Rehabilitation" July 9, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Prevention of Blindness", with J.W. Bettman July 16, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Consumer Health Protection", with California State Senator George Mascone" July 30, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Changes in Social Security", with John Richardson Regional Directory September 10, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Home Health Care Services", with Hadley D. Hall October 1, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Confrontation with Death", with Elizabeth Kubler-Ross October 8, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Reality Orientation in Rehabilitation", with Lars Peterson and Dorothy Scarbrough October 22, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "The Elderly as Volunteers" November 4, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Interview with U.S. Senator Alan Cranston" November 12, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Major Revisions in Social Security" November 19, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Medicare Revisions Aired" December 3, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Interview on California Legislation for the Elderly", with California Assemblyman Leo McCarthy December 10, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "San Francisco Downtown Senior Center", with Estella Booth January 9, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Social Security Changes" January 28, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Physical Health in the Later Years", with Bernard Blumberg February 4, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Interview with a Retired Rabbi", with Rabbi A.L. Feinberg February 11, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Berkeley Senior Center for Black Aged" February 28, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "The Elderly and Cancer", with Drs. Kligerman, Castro, and Rosenbaum March 7, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Economical and Safe Auto Use", with A. Thomas Rohner March 18, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Nursing Services for the Elderly", with Ann Allen March 25, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Meals on Wheels", with Dorrwin Jones April 1, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Nutrition", with Leona Shapiro April 8, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Glee Club and Bell Ringers of San Francisco Senior Center" April 22, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Widows", with Dr. Phyllis R. Silverman May 6, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "San Francisco widow and widower outreach program" May 27, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "California Nursing Homes", with State Assemblyman Leo T. McCarthy June 3, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Highway Safety for the Older Driver", with A. Thomas Rohner June 17, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Legal Aid for Elderly", with Ann Allen, R.N. July 15, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Gardening for the Older Person", with Leo Baroway July 8, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Nursing and the Elderly", with Ann Allen, R.N. July 15, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "North San Francisco Bay Programs for Older Men and Women", with Sally Schultz July 22, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Center for Learning in Retirement, University of California Extension Center, San Francisco", Panel Discussion July 29, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Creativity in the Later Years", with Jeffrey Smith, Ph.D. August 5, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Gift of Time GT-131", with Stanley Kilcoyne, interview August 12, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Geriatric Dentistry", with Sidney Epstein, D.D.S. August 19, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Older Japanese Americans", Panel Discussion August 26, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Community College Programs for Older Adults", with Elsa Bogosian and Mr. T. Murphy September 9, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Crime and the Older Person", with California Attorney-General Evella Younger and Mrs. June Sherwood September 16, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Food stamps for the Elderly", Panel Discussion September 23, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Estate Planning", Part I, with Peter E. Lippett September 30, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Estate Planning", Part II, with Peter E. Lippett October 7, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Multiphasic Screening", with Sam Sherman, M.D., and Morris Bunow November 4, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "The Aging Japanese", Panel Discussion November 25, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Gardening for the Elderly", with Leo Baroway December 2, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Choral Group, San Francisco Japanese Senior Center" December 16, 1973 (Box 3)
  - "Supplemental Security Income", Panel Discussion January 6, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Meat Economy", with Merle Ellis January 13, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Public Advocates", with Fred Hiestand January 20, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Gasoline Economy", with A. Thomas Rohmer January 27, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Supplementary Security Income", with Peter Coppelman February 3, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Euthanasia and the Elderly", with Marya Mannes February 10, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "California Legislative Council of Senior Citizens", with William Baird February 17, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Marin Colleges: "Emeritus College", Panel Discussion February 24, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Women Alone", with Tish Sommers, Milo Smith March 3, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Opus", with J. Otte and Paul Corwill March 17, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Senior Citizens Dental Care Program", with University of the Pacific March 31, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Crime and the Elderly", Part II April 17, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "The Gray Panthers", with Maggie Kuhn and Lillian Rabinowitz June 23, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Widows", with Mrs. Lynn Caine June 30, 1974 (Box 3)
  - "Crimes against the Elderly", with Captain Jeremiah Taylor February 23, 1975 (Box 3)
  - "Food Buying Cooperative for Seniors", with Pat Coates and Mrs. Sandi Piccini March 30, 1975 (Box 3)
  - "How Safe is Social Security", with Nelson Cruikshank April 27, 1975 (Box 3)
  - "U.S. Senate Special Committee on Aging", with William E. Oriol May 25, 1975 (Box 3)
  - "Why Survive?", with Robert N. Butler, M.D. June 29, 1975 (Box 4)
  - "Alameda County Office on Aging", with William E. Oriol May 25, 1975 (Box 4)
  - "The Aging Heart", with Leonard S. Karpman, M.D. September 28, 1975 (Box 4)
  - "Crimes Against Older People", with Nelder, Mellor, Boyer December 2, 1975 (Box 4)
  - "Grooming: Dresses for Older Women", with Dorothy W. Wagner January 25, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Grooming: Color in Dress", with Dorothy W. Wagner February 15, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Good Grooming: Hair and Make-up", with Dorothy W. Wagner February 22, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Senior Discount Program", with Harry H. Henry April 4, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "The Liberated Grandmother", with Mrs. D.C. Finkelhorn, Ph.D. April 25, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "San Francisco Senior Center Program for the Deaf Elderly", with Ms. Gay Nadler and Ms. Rhoda Clark June 27, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Paralegal Training for the Elderly", Panel Discussion July 25, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Menopause", with Dr. Minnie B. Goldberg, M.D. August 29, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "San Francisco Committee on Aging", with W. Patrick Magee, Director September 26, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Political Issues in Aging", Part I, with Wold and McCoy October 17, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Political Issues in Aging", Part II, with Bills and Musz October 24, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Political Issues in Aging", Part III, with J. Tunney and S. Hayakawa October 31, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "U.S. Senate Special Committee on Aging", with William E. Oriol December 12, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Christmas Program. San Francisco Senior Center Choral Group" December 19, 1976 (Box 4)
  - "Federal and State Income Tax Guides for the Elderly", with Mr. Holmes and Mr. Joseph February 19, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "Crime and the Elderly", Part I. F.B.I. and S.F.P.D. March 27, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "Crime and the Elderly", with Boone, Murphy, Kritelich, Harrington April 24, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "Lung Health", Part I May 29, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "Lung Health", Part II June 5, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "Smoking and Health", with William R. Pothner (?) October 30, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "The National Institute on Aging", with Robert N. Butler, M.D. November 27, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "Interview with Dr. Wilma Donahue and Dr. Clark Tibbitts December 18, 1977 (Box 4)
  - "Air Pollution and the Elderly", Part I January 15, 1978 (Box 4)
  - "Air Pollution and the Elderly", Part II January 22, 1978 (Box 4)
  - "Air Pollution and the Elderly", Part III January 29, 1978 (Box 4)
  - "Diabetes and the Aging", with Clinton Young, M.D. March 9, 1978 (Box 4)
  - "Organized Labor and its Older Members", with James G. Patton, Retired Member Department California Labor Federation July 9, 1978 (Box 4)